<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Fish On</string>
    <string name="start_journey_icon">Click anywhere to start your journey</string>
    <string name="application_start_image">Application start image</string>

    <string name="fish_me_next_quote">Fish me next quote</string>
    <string name="fishing_quote">Fishing Quote</string>
    <string name="sea_fishing">sea_fishing</string>
    <string name="river_fishing">river_fishing</string>
    <string name="lake_fishing">lake_fishing</string>
    <string name="your_personal_records">Your personal records:</string>
    <string name="adding_new_record">Adding new record</string>
    <string name="personal_record_image">Personal record image</string>
    <string name="add_new_record_tip_message">You can add your new personal record by clicking the plus icon.</string>
    <string name="you_must_fill_in_all_of_the_fields">You must fill in all of the fields.</string>
    <string name="adding_new_visited_place">Adding new visited place</string>
    <string name="adding_new_place_to_wish_list">Adding new location to wish list</string>
    <string name="add">ADD</string>
    <string name="modern_history_image">Modern history image</string>
    <string name="early_history_image">Early history image</string>
    <string name="pre_history_image">Pre history image</string>
    <string name="about_picture">About picture</string>
    <string name="sound">Sound</string>
    <string name="about_activity_information">\t\tThis application\'s idea was born by a lifelong passion of fishing.\n
        \t\tEvery fisherman at a given time in his life tries to remember the good old days when he was out fishing,
        enjoying a nice trip to the local creek. Maybe a long forgotten fishing spot or particular trophy catch?!\n\t\t\"Fish On\"
        lets you keep in track your fishing journey from the beginning till present day. You want to keep
        where you have already gone fishing or the places you want to visit next? This application lets you do that and
        much more. You can keep track of your personal records and store information about what species is the trophy
        catch, how much it weighs, its length and more…\n\t\tYou can learn more about the history of fishing, how it all started
        way back in the past till the modern days, check out the different types of fishing and their differences, learn basic
        tactics and maybe you can see yourself trying or learning something new.\n\t\tYou can also check out our  \"Home\" section
        where you can have a good laugh at a fishing quote to brighten up your day.\n\n\nKeep calm and Fish On</string>
    <string name="lake_fishing_information">\t\tLake fishing is when you fish a body of water that is classified to be a lake. A lake is classified as a body of relatively still water that is almost completely surrounded by land
        with a river or stream that feeds into it or drains from it. A lake that has fish that you can catch can either be man-made or natural, with natural lakes tending to have
                more successful results. There is not an international standard used to define the difference between a lake and a pond. Many people believe the difference between the two can either be size,
        how water is fed into it or a combination of both. Just because lakes are land locked doesn’t mean they are all freshwater. A lake can have a high concentration of salt, two examples are the Great Salt
        Lake and Lake Urmia. Depending on the concentration of salt, fish may or may not be able to survive or reach sufficient size to be worthy for fishing. Lakes, just like ponds, rivers and all other bodies
        of water will have creel limits. A creel limit is the amount of fish and/or size of fish you’re allowed to remove from that lake per day.\n\nLake Fishing Tips, Tricks and Techniques\n\nAre you ready to get
        out on the lake and catch some fish? Before you go you might want to read and use some of our lake fishing tips below. While these won’t be specific to any certain fish species, they can be used in
        combination with our fishing tips to make you a more skillful angler.\n\t\t- Inlets and Outlets are your Friend – Like humans, fish like specific temperatures and will generally hang around areas of a lake that
        they find comfortable. Places where water enters or drains from a lake will generally be much cooler and favorable to fish. \n\t\t- Bait fish like to hang around these areas, along with the big monster fish
        that eat them.\n\t\t- Choose the Right Bait – You can’t go wrong with natural freshwater bait such as cricket, worms, minnows, and leeches. Live bait can also be quite affordable. For example, Amazon has a
        great deal on live crickets. For artificial lures, we recommend fishing jigs. They are the most versatile in lakes because they can catch just about any type of freshwater fish. Our brand of choice is
        the Terminator Pro’s Jig.\n\t\t- As the Heat Index Rises – The hotter it gets outside the deeper you’ll need to fish. This is because fish tend to like cool temperatures and will retreat to deeper, cooler water
        as the temperature outside rises. During dusk and dawn fish will come to more shallow water to feed, some more shallow than others. You should research the specific type of fish you’re trying to catch
        in order to learn more.\n\t\t- Find Sunken Structures – Fish like to hang around structures that make them feel safe and that provide the opportunity to ambush other fish. Structures such as downed
                trees, branches and even man-made fish habitats are a great place to fish. You can easily build your own structure if you buy a kit such as the Cedars Porcupine Fish Attractor.\n\t\t- Look for
                 Weeds – A lot of big fish, like largemouth bass and northern pike, like to ambush their prey from a nice comfy weed bed. Locate some weed beds in the lake your fishing in and try getting your bait
                and/or lure in that area to see if you can coax a fish to bite. The weed beds that lead to deeper water and create a break line are the best honey pots.\n\t\t- Work with the Wind – On days with a strong
                breeze you can expect the bait fish to get pushed closer to shore, meaning the big fish will come closer to shore to feed. Watch for drift lines and follow them, they will lead to bait fish, which will
               in turn lead to big fish.\n</string>
    <string name="river_fishing_information">
\t\tRiver fishing is the method of fishing in a body of water that is defined by science to be a river. A river is a body of water that flows towards another river, ocean, lake or sea. You can fish a river from
        the shore, by wading or if the size and depth of the river make it possible, via a boat. A wide variety of different species of fish (including popular game fish) can be found inhabiting rivers or at
        least navigating them in order to reach spawning grounds or to catch fish when they migrate. Fishermen will need to use specific types of fishing rigs or bait casting methods due to the natural movement
        of a river. Rivers are used by invasive species to invade other bodies of water making it vital for humans to never introduce any foreign fish or bait fish to rivers.\n\t\tRiver fishing has a bad rap in
        some areas, especially rivers that run through urban areas. This is due to pollution and lack of water clarity. While pollution is an issue in urban areas, water clarity is just the result of sediment
        and mud being brought up from the movement of the water. Fishermen should always be aware of any advisories that are made by local or state agencies regarding the consumption of fish in specific
        rivers. Many rivers have dams and water locks that help control the flow of water. These structures can be a great place for large fish to congregate because of the water depth and temperature.\n\nRiver
        Fishing Tips, Tricks and Techniques\n\n\t\t- Get a Pair of Polarized Glasses – Depending on what river you plan on fishing in you may be able to see through the water with a good pair of polarized
        glasses. By being able to visually locate fish you can prevent a lot of wasted time searching for them.\n\t\t- Bottom Bounce Live Bait – An effective method for catching fish in a river is to use live
        bait and bounce it off the bottom. There are several types of fishing rigs that can accomplish this and will help present your bait more naturally. We recommend using the Carolina Rig. Also, sure you
        bounce your live bait with the current, and never against it.\n\t\t- Find the River’s Backwaters – Some of the most popular game fish that can be found in a river aren’t too fond of heavy currents.
        Largemouth bass are a great example of game fish that will inhabit backwater creeks that break off the river and reenter it downstream.\n\t\t- Find the Weeds – If you can locate a calm area of a river
        that has weed growth then you’ve most likely found a prime fishing location. Since weeds aren’t very common in rivers, fish will group together in calm areas of the river with weed growth. Don’t be
        shocked to find a monster largemouth bass hiding in one of these areas.\n\t\t- Fish Near the Islands – A lot of rivers will have islands in them and the slack area of these islands can hold some nice
        fish for you to catch. Be careful trying to wade out to any river islands because drop offs can appear out of nowhere and send you and your tackle downriver.\n\t\t- Talk to the Locals – The local bait
        and tackle shop or even fishermen along the shore can give you some great insight on what the best methods are for fishing in a nearby river. The actual location of fish in a river can be greatly
        affected by the weather and the moon. Locals who fish in the river often will be able to educate you on the best time and location to fish in the river.
    </string>
    <string name="sea_fishing_information">
        \t\tSaltwater fishing is a broad term used to describe the method of fishing in the ocean. Saltwater fishing can be done on shore (surf fishing), on a boat or on a pier. Live bait and artificial bait
        are used by saltwater anglers, which varies based on the type of fish the angler is trying to catch. Saltwater fishing is only available in states/countries that border an ocean or have an inlet river
        with a high level of salinity. Some of the greatest fighting fish are saltwater fish, such as the tuna or marlin. Saltwater fishing provides some of the best fishing experiences an angler can ever
        have.\nSome of the common types of saltwater fish sought out by anglers are bluefish, bonefish, cobia, cod, flounder, grouper, halibut, jewfish, kingfish, mackerel, marlin, pacific yellowtail, redfish,
        sailfish, sea trout, sharks, snapper, snook, striped bass, tarpon and tuna. The type of fishing tackle used can vary based on the species of fish the angler is trying to catch. Saltwater fishing charters
        are a billion dollar industry in tourist areas. In fact, if you’re new to saltwater fishing, a charter is a great way to get some experience and learn some tips from a professional saltwater fishermen.
        While they can be a little expensive, you could get a bunch of your buddies to go on a trip so you can all split the cost.\n\t\tSaltwater fishing is a broad term used to describe the method of fishing
        in the ocean. Saltwater fishing can be done on shore (surf fishing), on a boat or on a pier. Live bait and artificial bait are used by saltwater anglers, which varies based on the type of fish the
        angler is trying to catch. Saltwater fishing is only available in states/countries that border an ocean or have an inlet river with a high level of salinity. Some of the greatest fighting fish are
        saltwater fish, such as the tuna or marlin. Saltwater fishing provides some of the best fishing experiences an angler can ever have.\n\t\tSome of the common types of saltwater fish sought out by anglers
        are bluefish, bonefish, cobia, cod, flounder, grouper, halibut, jewfish, kingfish, mackerel, marlin, pacific yellowtail, redfish, sailfish, sea trout, sharks, snapper, snook, striped bass, tarpon and
        tuna. The type of fishing tackle used can vary based on the species of fish the angler is trying to catch. Saltwater fishing charters are a billion dollar industry in tourist areas. In fact, if you’re
        new to saltwater fishing, a charter is a great way to get some experience and learn some tips from a professional saltwater fishermen. While they can be a little expensive, you could get a bunch of
        your buddies to go on a trip so you can all split the cost.\n\nSaltwater Fishing Tips, Tricks and Tactics\n\n\t\t- Use the Right Fishing Knot – The best way to make sure you don’t lose that next world
        record fish is to make sure you’re using the right knot. You need to learn a fishing knot that can retain 100% of its strength when tied, and only the bimini twist (aka 20 times around know) can do just
        that. The right knot can make the difference between a big catch, or a big disappointment. \n\t\t- Keep Live Bait in Tip Top Shape – If you’re using live bait it’s important to keep it in the best shape
        possible. Make sure to always keep live bait out of direct sunlight and if you have aquatic bait like minnows then make sure to buy a water bait aerator to keep sufficient oxygen levels. If you don’t
        have an aerator then make sure that you change the water every 2 hours. Warm water can’t hold as much oxygen as cool water. \n\t\t- Talk to the Locals – You should talk to your local tackle shop
        employee in order to find out what’s going on in the area you plan to fish in. They’ll know what’s going on and what the best bait to use is at the time of year you’re fishing in. You might even
        want to consider joining a local angler’s club where anglers get together to swap stories, plan trips and drink beer. \n\t\t- Finding the Spot for Fishing – One easy way to snag some monster saltwater
        fish is to research the type of structure they like to live in and then locate those structures where you plan to fish. There are tons of resources on the internet to locate natural and man-made
        structures in your area. Avoid paying for any maps that claim to have secret locations and/or structures, nine times out of ten you can locate these structures with free research. \n\t\t- Watch Your
        Leader – If you’re using a leader then it’s important to keep an eye on the knot area of where your line is tied to your leader. This area and about a foot or two above it tends to get damaged pretty
        quickly, especially if you’re surf fishing. You’ll want to cut off any bad or frayed areas and retie your leader. Don’t lose a big monster catch because you were too lazy to check your leader knot.
        And also make sure to use a quality leader. \n\t\t- Preserve the Experience for Others – The only way we can sustain commercial and recreational fishing in the future is to work together. Use a circle
        hook when fishing to prevent injury to the fish. Never keep your catch out of the water longer than you can hold your own breath. The slime that covers a fish protects it from bacteria and infection,
        so do your best to not remove this slime. Also, don’t forget to practice catch and release, especially during spawning seasons! \n\t\t- Protect Your Investment – Good fishing tackle isn’t cheap,
        especially if you have a quality saltwater reel. So don’t get yourself in the situation of having to replace it. It’s a good idea to soak your reel in a bucket of freshwater for 2 to 4 hours after
        saltwater fishing to ensure you get all the saltwater off of your line and reel.
    </string>
    <string name="pre_history_information">
        \t\tFishing is an ancient practice that dates back at least to the Upper Paleolithic period which began about 40,000 years ago. Isotopic analysis of the skeletal remains of Tianyuan man, a 40,000-year-old
        modern human from eastern Asia, has shown that he regularly consumed freshwater fish. Archaeological features such as shell middens, discarded fish bones and cave paintings show that sea foods were
        important for survival and consumed in significant quantities. During this period, most people lived a hunter-gatherer lifestyle and were, of necessity, constantly on the move. However, where there are
        early examples of permanent settlements (though not necessarily permanently occupied) such as those at Lepenski Vir, they are almost always associated with fishing as a major source of food.\n\t\tSpearfishing
        with barbed poles (harpoons) was widespread in palaeolithic times. Cosquer cave in Southern France contains cave art over 16,000 years old, including drawings of seals which appear to have been
        harpooned. \n\t\t The Neolithic culture and technology spread worldwide between 4,000 and 8,000 years ago. With the new technologies of farming and pottery came basic forms of the main fishing methods
        that are still used today. \n\t\t From 7500 to 3000 years ago, Native Americans of the California coast were known to engage in fishing with gorge hook and line tackle. In addition, some tribes are known
        to have used plant toxins to induce torpor in stream fish to enable their capture. \n\t\t Copper harpoons were known to the seafaring Harappans well into antiquity. Early hunters in India include the
        Mincopie people, aboriginal inhabitants of India's Andaman and Nicobar islands, who have used harpoons with long cords for fishing since early times.
    </string>
    <string name="early_history_starting_information">
        \t\tThe ancient river Nile was full of fish; fresh and dried fish were a staple food for much of the population. The Egyptians invented various implements and methods for fishing and these are clearly illustrated in tomb
        scenes, drawings, and papyrus documents. Simple reed boats served for fishing. Woven nets, weir baskets made from willow branches, harpoons and hook and line (the hooks having a length of between eight
        millimetres and eighteen centimetres) were all being used. By the 12th dynasty, metal hooks with barbs were being used. As is fairly common today, the fish were clubbed to death after capture.
        Nile perch, catfish and eels were among the most important fish. Some representations hint at fishing being pursued as a pastime.
    </string>
    <string name="early_history_next_information">
        \t\tThere are numerous references to fishing in ancient literature; in most cases, however, the descriptions of nets and fishing-gear do not go into detail, and the equipment is described in general terms\n\t\t
        Unlike in Minoan culture, fishing scenes are rarely represented in ancient Greek culture, a reflection of the low social status of fishing. There is a wine cup, dating from c. 500 BC, that shows a boy
        crouched on a rock with a fishing-rod in his right hand and a basket in his left. In the water below there is a rounded object of the same material with an opening on the top. This has been identified
        as a fish-cage used for keeping live fish, or as a fish-trap. It is clearly not a net. This object is currently in the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston. \n\t\t Oppian of Corycus, a Greek author wrote a major
        treatise on sea fishing, the Halieulica or Halieutika, composed between 177 and 180. This is the earliest such work to have survived intact to the modern day. Oppian describes various means of fishing
        including the use of nets cast from boats, scoop nets held open by a hoop, spears and tridents, and various traps "which work while their masters sleep". Oppian\'s description of fishing with a "motionless"
        net is also very interesting: \n\t\t The fishers set up very light nets of buoyant flax and wheel in a circle round about while they violently strike the surface of the sea with their oars and make a
        din with sweeping blow of poles. At the flashing of the swift oars and the noise the fish bound in terror and rush into the bosom of the net which stands at rest, thinking it to be a shelter: foolish
        fishes which, frightened by a noise, enter the gates of doom. Then the fishers on either side hasten with the ropes to draw the net ashore. \n\t\t The Greek historian Polybius (ca 203 BC–120 BC), in his
        Histories, describes hunting for swordfish by using a harpoon with a barbed and detachable head. \n\t\t Pictorial evidence of Roman fishing comes from mosaics which show fishing from boats with rod and
        line as well as nets. Various species such as conger, lobster, sea urchin, octopus and cuttlefish are illustrated.] In a parody of fishing, a type of gladiator called retiarius was armed with a trident
        and a casting-net. He would fight against the murmillo, who carried a short sword and a helmet with the image of a fish on the front.
    </string>
    <string name="modern_history_information">
        \t\tModern reel design had begun in England during the latter part of the 18th century, and the predominant model in use was known as the Nottingham reel\'s. The reel was a wide drum which spooled
        out freely, and was ideal for allowing the bait to drift along way out with the current. Geared multiplying reels never successfully caught on in Britain, but had more success in the United States,
        where similar models were modified by George Snyder of Kentucky into his bait-casting reel, the first American-made design in 1810.\n\t\tTackle design began to improve from the 1880s. The introduction
        of new woods to the manufacture of fly rods made it possible to cast flies into the wind on silk lines, instead of horse hair. These lines allowed for a much greater casting distance. However, these
        early fly lines proved troublesome as they had to be coated with various dressings to make them float and needed to be taken off the reel and dried every four hours or so to prevent them from becoming
        waterlogged. Another negative consequence was that it became easy for the much longer line to get into a tangle - this was called a tangle in Britain, and a backlash in the US. This problem
        spurred the invention of the regulator to evenly spool the line out and prevent tangling. \n\t\t By the mid to late 19th century, expanding leisure opportunities for the middle and lower classes began
        to have its effect on fly fishing, which steadily grew in mass appeal.\n\nRecreational fishing\n\nRecreational fishing and the closely related (nearly synonymous) sport fishing describe fishing for
        pleasure or competition. The practice commonly involves the use of a hook to attempt to catch fish, in which case the term angling also is applied. Recreational fishing has conventions, rules,
        licensing restrictions, and laws that limit the way in which fish may be caught. The International Game Fishing Association (IGFA) makes and oversees a set of voluntary obligations. Typically,
        these prohibit the use of nets and the catching of fish with hooks not in the mouth. Enforceable regulations are put in place by governments to ensure sustainable practice amongst anglers. For
        example in the Republic of Ireland, the Central Fisheries Board oversees the implementation of all angling regulations, which include controls on angling lures, baits, and number of hooks, as well
        as licensing regimes and other conservation based restrictions. \n\t\t In addition to capturing fish for food, recreational anglers also enjoy keeping a log of fish caught and submitting trophy sized
        fish to independent record keeping bodies. In the Republic of Ireland, the Irish Specimen Fish Committee verifies and publicizes the capture of specimen (i.e. trophy) fish caught on rod and line by
        anglers in Ireland, both in freshwater and at sea. The Committee also ratifies Irish record rod caught fish. It also maintains a set of 'fair play' regulations to ensure fish are caught in accordance
        with accepted angling norms. \n\t\tIn angling, it is sometimes expected or required that all fish be returned to the water (catch and release). The practice, however, is viewed by some with
        disapproval as they consider it unethical to inflict pain on a fish for fun or sport and not for reasons of capturing food. Anglers deny this charge, pointing out that fish commonly feed on hard
        and spiky prey items, and as such can be expected to have tough mouths, and also that some fish will re-take a lure they have just been hooked on, a behavior that is unlikely if being hooked were
        painful. There is also some research showing that certain types of fish such as catfish, do not have nerves around their mouth, most likely due to the fact that they eat animals such as crawfish t
        hat can pinch.
    </string>
    <string name="initial_fishing_quote">\"There’s a fine line between fishing and standing on the shore like an idiot.\"\n\n\t\t\t\t(Steven Wright)</string>
    <string name="species_hint">Species</string>
    <string name="country_hint">Country</string>
    <string name="year_caught_hint">Year caught</string>
    <string name="weight_in_kg_hint">Weight in kg.</string>
    <string name="length_in_metres_hint">Length in metres</string>
    <string name="country_hint">Country</string>
    <string name="name_hint">Name</string>
    <string-array name="water_basin_types_array">
        <item>River</item>
        <item>Lake</item>
        <item>Sea</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>
